[{"question":"Which year was ThoughtWorks founded?","correct_choice":"1993","choices":["1993","1998","2002"]},{"question":"Martin Fowler is known as ThoughtWorks","correct_choice":"Chief Scientist","choices":["Bearded Wonder","CTO","Chief Scientist"]},{"question":"ThoughtWorks has offices in how many countries?","correct_choice":"8","choices":["8","4","10"]},{"question":"Which of these is a prototype-based language?","correct_choice":"Io","choices":["Erlang","Haskell","Io"]},{"question":"Which of these is a pure functional language?","correct_choice":"Haskell","choices":["Haskell","Scala","Ruby"]},{"question":"Which Design Pattern would you use if you wanted to construct a complex object?","correct_choice":"Builder","choices":["Abstract Factory","Builder","Singleton"]},{"question":"What is the abbreviation for Amazon's AWS column based data store?","correct_choice":"SimpleDB","choices":["SimpleDB","S3","EC2"]},{"question":"Is ThoughtWorks a Product company?","correct_choice":"No","choices":["Maybe","No","Yes"]},{"question":"Is ThoughtWorks Studios a product company?","correct_choice":"Yes","choices":["Yes","No","Maybe"]},{"question":"How many products does ThoughtWorks Studios have?","correct_choice":"3","choices":["2","3","5"]},{"question":"Which of the below is NOT a recognised \"flavour\" of Agile?","correct_choice":"Rational Unified Process","choices":["Rational Unified Process","FDD","Crystal Clear"]},{"question":"What are the responsibilities of these roles in a stand-up?","correct_choice":"Pigs talk, chickens listen","choices":["Pigs talk, chickens listen","Pigs listen, chickens talk","Pigs oink, chicken: kokoriko!"]},{"question":"How many (a) values and (b) principles are listed at agilemanifesto.org","correct_choice":"4 and 12","choices":["4 and 12","5 and 10","4 and 11"]},{"question":"In order, what are the steps when doing Test Driven Development?","correct_choice":"Red/Green/Refactor","choices":["Green/Red/Refactor","Red/Refactor/Green","Red/Green/Refactor"]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT the name for a coding problem set for ThoughtWorks development candidates?","correct_choice":"Debt Chasers","choices":["Debt Chasers","Mars Rover","Trains"]},{"question":"Which of these speakers have NOT presented at every Agile Australia conference so far?","correct_choice":"Martin Fowler","choices":["Nigel Dalton (Lonely Planet, LunaTractor)","Fred Flintsone","Martin Fowler"]},{"question":"The majority of the services provided by AWS are best described as:","correct_choice":"IaaS","choices":["IaaS","PaaS","SaaS"]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT marketed as a functional programming language?","correct_choice":"Scala","choices":["Scala","Scheme","Clojure"]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT on the most recent edition of the Tech Radar?","correct_choice":"Delphi","choices":["DevOps","Delphi","Clojure"]},{"question":"The seminal software text colloquially referred to as the \"Gang of Four\" is about?","correct_choice":"Design Patterns","choices":["Design Patterns","Functional Programming","Scrum"]},{"question":"Which of the following user groups is NOT regularly hosted in a ThoughtWorks office in Australia?","correct_choice":"AWSUG","choices":["Alt.NET","Melb.js","AWSUG"]},{"question":"If you overheard a ThoughtWorks developer talking about \"Passenger\", \"Mongrel\" and \"Bundler\", what language do you think they are talking about?","correct_choice":"Ruby","choices":["C#","Java","Ruby"]},{"question":"Where are you most likely to see the \"Given.... When.... Then....\" format appear?","correct_choice":"An acceptance test","choices":["An acceptance test","A CI dashboard","A user story"]},{"question":"How would a typical ThoughtWorks dev rank these version control systems in order of preference (most to least)?","correct_choice":"Git/CVS/ClearCase ","choices":["ClearCase/CVS/Git","Git/CVS/ClearCase ","CVS/ClearCase/Git"]},{"question":"Pick the odd one out:","correct_choice":"Puppet","choices":["Selenium","Concordian","Puppet"]},{"question":"One of these acronyms is NOT an approach commonly used by ThoughtWorks teams - which one? ","correct_choice":"ODD","choices":["ATDD","BDD","ODD"]},{"question":"Is Selenium a ThoughtWorks Product?","correct_choice":"No","choices":["No","Yes","Maybe"]},{"question":"What is ThoughtWorks Studios?","correct_choice":"Agile software solutions and training division of ThoughtWorks","choices":["Sister Company","Partner Company","Agile software solutions and training division of ThoughtWorks"]},{"question":"What is Twist?","correct_choice":"Test Automation tool","choices":["Test Management tool","Test Automation tool","Platform"]},{"question":"When is Planning Poker used?","correct_choice":"When estimating a story card","choices":["During inception for prioritization of story cards","When estimating a story card","After a showcase to bet on the next iteration velocity"]},{"question":"Which one is NOT a ThoughtWorks core value?","correct_choice":"Protecting our brand","choices":["Protecting our brand","Creating a better world","Having fun"]},{"question":"Failed attempts at refactoring are also called?","correct_choice":"Refuctoring or Refactorbating","choices":["Refuctoring","Refactorbating","Refuctoring or Refactorbating"]},{"question":"A computer bug that disappears or alters its characteristics when an attempt is made to study it, is also called?","correct_choice":"Heisenbug","choices":["Super bug","Bugzilla","Heisenbug"]},{"question":"What language is most closely associated with the actors model of concurrency?","correct_choice":"Erlang","choices":["Erlang","Ruby","Java"]},{"question":"What does the EC2 acronym stand for in the Amazon Web Services cloud offering?","correct_choice":"Elastic Compute Cloud","choices":["Electric Computation 2","Elastic Compute Cloud","Enterprise Cloud Connection"]},{"question":"Who wrote the first code compiler?","correct_choice":"Grace Hopper","choices":["Ada Lovelace","Grace Hopper","Kay McNulty"]},{"question":"In which decade was Ruby invented?","correct_choice":"90's","choices":["90's","80's","00's"]},{"question":"Which language was developed first?","correct_choice":"Lisp","choices":["Basic","Lisp","Cobol"]},{"question":"Who is the author of the book Continuous Delivery?","correct_choice":"Jez Humble","choices":["Jim Highsmith","Jez Humble","Martin Fowler"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the ADOPT ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"DevOps","choices":["Acceptance tinkering","Scrum Certification","DevOps"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the ADOPT ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Subversion","choices":["NoSQL","Subversion","Code in configuration"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the ADOPT ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Javascript as first class language","choices":["HAML","Domain specific languages","Javascript as first class language"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the ADOPT ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"HTML5","choices":["Coffeescript","Future of Java","HTML5"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the ADOPT ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"JRuby","choices":["Heroku","Tablet","JRuby"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the Trial ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Continuous Deployment","choices":["Continuous Deployment","Database based integration","Continuous Delivery"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the Trial ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Selenium 2 testing of mobile websites","choices":["Selenium 2 testing of mobile websites","ESB","Code in configuration"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the Trial ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Scala","choices":["Logic in stored procedures","F#","Scala"]},{"question":"Which of the following appears on the Trial ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Offline mobile webapps","choices":["Cloud Foundry","Offline mobile webapps","Node.js"]},{"question":"Which of the following statements is NOT from the Agile Manifesto?","correct_choice":" Responding to change over processes and tools","choices":[" Responding to change over processes and tools","Customer collaboration over contract negotiation","Working software over comprehensive documentation"]},{"question":"Agile teams should be?","correct_choice":"Empowered to make local decisions","choices":["Managed closely to avoid scope creep","Empowered to make local decisions","Use a lot of 'spikes' to ensure performance"]},{"question":"Which of the following does NOT appear on the Adopt ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Continuous Deployment","choices":["Automate database deployment","Evolutionary architecture","Continuous Deployment"]},{"question":"Which of the following does NOT appear on the Adopt ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Next gen test tools","choices":["Git","Next gen test tools","Github"]},{"question":"Which of the following does NOT appear on the Assess ring of the ThoughtWorks Technology radar?","correct_choice":"Coffeescript","choices":["Future of Java","Clojure","Coffeescript"]},{"question":"ThoughtWorks University is located in?","correct_choice":"India","choices":["Chicago","India","London"]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT a ThoughtWorks product?","correct_choice":"Jira","choices":["Go","Mingle","Jira"]},{"question":"How many employees does ThoughtWorks have globally?","correct_choice":"1800","choices":["1800","1500","1000"]},{"question":"The winning solution for ThoughtWorks Mars Rover problem (check out our ThoughtWorkers T-shirts) was written in:","correct_choice":"Perl","choices":["Perl","Ruby","Java"]},{"question":"ThoughtWorks does NOT have office in which country?","correct_choice":"France","choices":["France","China","India"]}]